<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WindowsServer on CLOUD DATACENTER &amp; DEVICE MANAGEMENT BLOG</title>
    <link>/tags/windowsserver/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WindowsServer on CLOUD DATACENTER &amp; DEVICE MANAGEMENT BLOG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 05:09:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/windowsserver/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Spaces Direct with 3 VMs using Windows Server 2016 Technical Preview 5</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-05-01-storage-spaces-direct-with-3-vms-using-windows-server-2016-technical-preview-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 14:52:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-05-01-storage-spaces-direct-with-3-vms-using-windows-server-2016-technical-preview-5/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post let’s looks at creating a Storage Spaces Direct Hyper Converged solution using three virtual machines. For production deployment, it is recommended to use physical servers instead of virtual machines. I will be using Windows Server 2016 Technical Preview 5 version which was just released few days back for this blog post.
Before I move any further, I would like to highlight some of the key features introduced part of Windows Server 2016 Technical Preview 5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Server 2016 &amp;#038; System Center 2016 Technical Preview 4</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-11-27-windows-server-2016-system-center-2016-technical-preview-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 14:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-11-27-windows-server-2016-system-center-2016-technical-preview-4/</guid>
      <description> Nano Server (DNS Server / IIS Server roles and also previously included scale out File Server &amp;amp; Hyper-V Role) Windows Containers Site-Aware Failover Cluster, Workgroup and Multi-domain Clusters Hyper-V Virtual Machine Resiliency Cloud Witness Cloud Operating System Rolling Upgrade Storage Spaces Direct Storage Replica   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TECH2014 Houston Sessions by Cluster Team</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-05-19-tech2014-houston-sessions-by-cluster-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 13:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-05-19-tech2014-houston-sessions-by-cluster-team/</guid>
      <description>Cluster Product group presented multiple sessions at TECH2014 which took place in Houston from 12th to 15th May 2014. please find below list of sessions which were presented at the event.
1) ****DCIM-B354 Failover Clustering: What’s New in Windows Server 2012 R2
2) ****DCIM-B364 Step-by-Step to Deploying Microsoft SQL Server 2014 with Cluster Shared Volumes
3) ****DCIM-B349 Software-Defined Storage in Windows Server 2012 R2 and Microsoft System Center 2012 R2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 8.1 / Server 2012 R2 RTM Now Available on MSDN &amp;#038; TECHNET</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-09-11-windows-8-1-server-2012-r2-rtm-now-available-on-msdn-technet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 11:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-09-11-windows-8-1-server-2012-r2-rtm-now-available-on-msdn-technet/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft announced yesterday that they will be making Windows 8.1 RTM / Windows Server 2012 RTM &amp;amp; Visual Studio 2013 RC made available for developer community based on feedback received. This was a slight deviation from previous communication when both products hit internal RTM milestone. however I’m extremely pleased for being able to obtain RTM bits for both Windows Client &amp;amp; Windows Server prior to GA milestone which is 18th October.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Windows Server 8 Beta</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-03-02-installing-windows-server-8-beta-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2012 23:45:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-03-02-installing-windows-server-8-beta-2/</guid>
      <description>Finally most eagerly anticipated Windows 8 next release has been announced by Microsoft. This is the second public release of Windows 8 after releasing Windows 8 Develop Preview edition was announced on 29th February 2012.
I have already downloaded Windows 8 Beta and I’m going to have a look at installation process in this blog post. if you haven’t yet downloaded Windows 8 beta, you can download from TechNet Evaluation Center by accessing following link</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>