<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL on CLOUD DATACENTER &amp; DEVICE MANAGEMENT BLOG</title>
    <link>/categories/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQL on CLOUD DATACENTER &amp; DEVICE MANAGEMENT BLOG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 22:11:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server 2016 Failover Cluster Instances in Azure</title>
      <link>/posts/2017-02-19-sql-server-2016-failover-cluster-instances-in-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 22:11:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2017-02-19-sql-server-2016-failover-cluster-instances-in-azure/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft recently announced additional support scenarios for using Guest Clusters in Azure. In this blog post, let’s have a look how we can build a two node SQL 2016 Guest clustering in Azure using Windows Server 2016 Storage Spaces Direct.
Utilizing Guest clusters in Azure enables mission critical application such as a SQL backend to function with greater availability if a single instance fails. By using Failover clustering and also placing virtual machines in an availability set, ensure that the application can work regardless of a hardware failure / Host updates or an application instance failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Manager 2012 R2 with SQL 2014</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-06-24-service-manager-2012-r2-with-sql-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 15:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-06-24-service-manager-2012-r2-with-sql-2014/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft announced support for SQL 2014 with Update Rollup 6 for System Center Service Manager 2012 R2. While working on a recent project, I wanted to explore the possibility of building a fresh instance of Service Manager 2012 R2 with SQL 2014.
Since UR 6 update is not slipstreamed in to System Center Service Manager R2 Media, if you try to install it against a SQL 2014 Server, you will not be able to proceed ahead with the install.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SQL Server 2014 General Availability</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-04-02-sql-server-2014-general-availability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 13:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-04-02-sql-server-2014-general-availability/</guid>
      <description>Today morning, Microsoft announced general availability for next major release of Microsoft SQL Server product which is called “SQL Server 2014”.
I have listed below some of the key highlights of SQL Server 2014 release
  Up to 30x In-Memory OLTP performance gains New Cloud Migration Wizard Clustered Columnstore indexes  –
 please find below official announcement from Microsoft SQL Product team blog
http://blogs.technet.com/b/dataplatforminsider/archive/2014/04/01/sql-server-2014-now-generally-available.aspx
SQL Server 2014 Datasheet</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>