<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Clustering on CLOUD DATACENTER &amp; DEVICE MANAGEMENT BLOG</title>
    <link>/tags/clustering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Clustering on CLOUD DATACENTER &amp; DEVICE MANAGEMENT BLOG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 13:45:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/clustering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TECH2014 Houston Sessions by Cluster Team</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-05-19-tech2014-houston-sessions-by-cluster-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2014 13:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-05-19-tech2014-houston-sessions-by-cluster-team/</guid>
      <description>Cluster Product group presented multiple sessions at TECH2014 which took place in Houston from 12th to 15th May 2014. please find below list of sessions which were presented at the event.
1) ****DCIM-B354 Failover Clustering: What’s New in Windows Server 2012 R2
2) ****DCIM-B364 Step-by-Step to Deploying Microsoft SQL Server 2014 with Cluster Shared Volumes
3) ****DCIM-B349 Software-Defined Storage in Windows Server 2012 R2 and Microsoft System Center 2012 R2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to build a cluster when sharing the same network for iSCSI Storage</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-02-19-unable-to-build-a-cluster-when-sharing-the-same-network-for-iscsi-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2013 16:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-02-19-unable-to-build-a-cluster-when-sharing-the-same-network-for-iscsi-storage/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we will look at an issue relating to sharing the same iSCSI Storage network for cluster communication. Looking at networking best practices for creating a Windows Server 2012 Failover Cluster, it is recommend that we separate iSCSI storage traffic from Cluster Communication. iSCSI needs to be on a separate dedicated network and it is not recommended to share iSCSI Storage Trafic &amp;amp; Network communication traffic.
At the time of cluster being created, it will automatically disable the network for cluster communication if it is used for iSCSI Storage traffic and this will cause the cluster creation to fail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s new in Windows Server 2012 Failover Clustering–Part 1</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-01-01-whats-new-in-windows-server-2012-failover-clusteringpart-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 14:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-01-01-whats-new-in-windows-server-2012-failover-clusteringpart-1/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we will have a look at new capabilities &amp;amp; features introduced in Failover Clustering with Windows Server 2012. We will also discuss on features which were improved from Windows Server 2008 R2 Failover Clustering.
Lets first look at scalability improvements in Failover Clustering.
With Windows Server 2012 Failover Clustering, we can now scale up to 64 Nodes compared to 16 nodes which was possible on Windows Server 2008 R2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>