<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personal on CLOUD DATACENTER &amp; DEVICE MANAGEMENT BLOG</title>
    <link>/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personal on CLOUD DATACENTER &amp; DEVICE MANAGEMENT BLOG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 08:59:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Awarded as a Microsoft MVP for 6th consecutive year</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-07-09-awarded-as-a-microsoft-mvp-for-6th-consecutive-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 08:59:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-07-09-awarded-as-a-microsoft-mvp-for-6th-consecutive-year/</guid>
      <description>2nd July I was re-awarded as a Microsoft MVP for 6th consecutive year. Over the years, it has been a great privilege being part of this Microsoft MVP community, to be able to share and also learn from others.
This year, I’m part of the Cloud &amp;amp; Datacenter Management award category due to some of the recent changes in the MVP Program. Previously I was awarded for High Availability award category for my contributions relating to Windows Server / SQL Server High Availability and since OCT 2015, Microsoft made changes to bring Windows Server / System Center award categories together under Cloud &amp;amp; Datacenter Management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Available! Windows Server and System Center 2016 Technical Preview 5!</title>
      <link>/posts/2016-04-29-now-available-windows-server-and-system-center-2016-technical-preview-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 09:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2016-04-29-now-available-windows-server-and-system-center-2016-technical-preview-5/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft has released Technical Preview 5 for Windows Server 2016 and System Center 2016. This release is the last release before moving in to General Availability later this year. Microsoft made number of improvements within this Technical Preview 5 for both Windows Server &amp;amp; System Center products. To find out more on what’s improved / add please have a look at below resources
What’s New in Windows Server 2016 Technical Preview 5</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Nano Server on a Physical Machine using Windows Server 2016 Technical Preview 4</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-11-28-installing-nano-servertechnical-preview-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 09:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-11-28-installing-nano-servertechnical-preview-4/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post we will look at how to deploy a Nano Server instance using Windows Server Technical Preview 4.
First of all there are two ways of deploying Nano Sever. First method is for deploying Nano Server on a VM and the Second method is for deploying Nano Server on a Physical machine. In this blog post, we will look at deploying Nano Server on a Physical machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 8.1 Preview is now available</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-06-27-windows-8-1-preview-is-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 01:02:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-06-27-windows-8-1-preview-is-now-available/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft just announced availability for Windows 8.1 Preview at the Build Conference. 8.1 Preview update can be downloaded as an update using Windows Store or it can also be downloaded as an ISO file. please use below to obtain Windows 8.1 Preview version.
](http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-8/download-preview &amp;ldquo;http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-8/download-preview&amp;quot;)
http://windows.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-8/download-preview</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>