<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows Client on CLOUD DATACENTER &amp; DEVICE MANAGEMENT BLOG</title>
    <link>/categories/windows-client/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows Client on CLOUD DATACENTER &amp; DEVICE MANAGEMENT BLOG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 07:38:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/windows-client/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Updating Configuration Manager Client Package with Client Agent Hotfixes</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-02-10-updating-configuration-manager-client-package-with-client-agent-hotfixes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2015 07:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-02-10-updating-configuration-manager-client-package-with-client-agent-hotfixes/</guid>
      <description>This is a quick post, to detail how we can install Configuration Manager client updates as a part of Client Deployment within Configuration Manager 2012 R2. There are multiple ways to achieve this task and the below explained method would be the easiest to configure.
Problem: Due to multiple Cumulative updates for Configuration Manager 2012 R2, it’s required for us to update all Configuration Manager Clients and also any new machines that gets built will also need to be applied with client update package</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 10 Preview–January Build Now Available (9926)</title>
      <link>/posts/2015-01-24-windows-10-previewjanuary-build-now-available-9926/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2015 08:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2015-01-24-windows-10-previewjanuary-build-now-available-9926/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft has just released latest preview build for Windows 10 which is known as the January Build or Technical Preview 2. This release contains build version 9926. Latest build comes with Cortana and XBOX features which were demonstrated few days back at the Public event held by Microsoft.
In order to obtain this build, you need to either be a Windows Insider (join for free https://insider.windows.com) or it’s possible to download from MSDN Subscription.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Windows 10</title>
      <link>/posts/2014-10-01-announcing-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 07:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2014-10-01-announcing-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today Microsoft announced Windows 10, next version of the client Operating System. Following the announcement today, Technical Preview to be available on 1stOctober (US Date &amp;amp; Time), which will be available for us later tonight or early tomorrow.
Microsoft is also introducing Windows Insider Program, which allows a user to download Windows 10 Technical Preview and also provide feedback to Microsoft.
Official Announcement -&amp;gt; http://blogs.windows.com/bloggingwindows/2014/09/30/announcing-windows-10/
Windows Insider Program -&amp;gt; http://preview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows 8.1 / Server 2012 R2 RTM Now Available on MSDN &amp;#038; TECHNET</title>
      <link>/posts/2013-09-11-windows-8-1-server-2012-r2-rtm-now-available-on-msdn-technet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 11:20:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2013-09-11-windows-8-1-server-2012-r2-rtm-now-available-on-msdn-technet/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft announced yesterday that they will be making Windows 8.1 RTM / Windows Server 2012 RTM &amp;amp; Visual Studio 2013 RC made available for developer community based on feedback received. This was a slight deviation from previous communication when both products hit internal RTM milestone. however I’m extremely pleased for being able to obtain RTM bits for both Windows Client &amp;amp; Windows Server prior to GA milestone which is 18th October.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unable to Sign-in to Skype–Windows 8 Release Preview</title>
      <link>/posts/2012-06-07-unable-to-sign-in-to-skypewindows-8-release-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 23:01:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2012-06-07-unable-to-sign-in-to-skypewindows-8-release-preview/</guid>
      <description>I noticed that I’m unable to sign-in to Skype on my Windows 8 Release Preview version. I have tried to find a solution for this login issue and finally I discovered that we can delete shared.xml file and fix this issue.
first you need to make sure that Skype is not running, if its running you need to close it or end taskafter closing Skype navigate towards “%appdata%/Skype” and delete shared.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>